[{"id": "5aab2eb858d116dab4aecb41", "question": "Who played the role of Wayne Szalinski in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Rick Moranis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99bea21a8909e5c332d31", "question": "Who wrote the 1981 novel \"Who Censored Roger Rabbit?\"?", "answer": "Gary K. Wolf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2eca58d116dab4aecb42", "question": "What is the name of the inventor in the 1989 film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\"?", "answer": "Wayne Szalinski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c3", "question": "What company was formerly known as the \"Computing-Tabulating-Recording Company\"?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e4", "question": "Lemurs are found almost entirely on which isolated island?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38f", "question": "Who did Nathuram Godse murder in 1948?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec9", "question": "\"Dig 'em Frog\" was the mascot for which Kellogg's breakfast cereal?", "answer": "Honey Smacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c20c9d816e292245c29", "question": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II using what?", "answer": "English artist Andy Brown created a portrait of Queen Elizabeth II out of 1000 used and unused tea bags.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9e8", "question": "What country borders Libya on the East?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590721963745b36be73039f8", "question": "What were Frosty the Snowman\u2019s eyes made out of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e98bcebfabb9c85d8a96e", "question": "Which former Archbishop of Canterbury was burned alive in 1556?", "answer": "Thomas Cranmer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e805d2de59ea584496feac", "question": "Which town was severly damaged by the Boland Earthquake in September 1969?", "answer": "Tulbagh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b2f84fda37788a9a1dbf", "question": "Who is Tasmania named after?", "answer": "Abel Tasman", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339479", "question": "Who won an Oscar for Best Actor in 1993 and again in 1994?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fad", "question": "In ballet, a lowering of the body by bending the knee is called a what?", "answer": "Fondu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa42b5c73aa70ea0b70b14", "question": "Fort-de-France is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Martinique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adcc", "question": "Which British liner did a German U-boat sink on May 7th 1915?", "answer": "RMS Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c0", "question": "What is the more common name for Scapula?", "answer": "Shoulder blade", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d30", "question": "What novel is Aldous Huxley's fifth novel?", "answer": "A Brave New World", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdffac71cf6db9ac4808cf1", "question": "What country was the modern bicycle invented in?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c364", "question": "What astrological chart takes its name from a Greek word meaning \"circle of little animals\"?", "answer": "Zodiac", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd5", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"Q\"?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b92", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Monkees\" were made?", "answer": "58", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdc", "question": "What TV veteran originated the role of neat freak Felix Unger in \"The Odd Couple\" on Broadway?", "answer": "Art Carney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d9", "question": "What year did Vladimir Nabokov first publish the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "1955", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbc922560f0007efaba0e58", "question": "What is the capital of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9b", "question": "What was the fictional town that was the setting for the soap opera \"All My Children\"?", "answer": "Pine Valley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a449", "question": "In which city are the Petronas Towers located?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ccff877e98cb97778a30", "question": "What shape is in the center of Switzerland's flag?", "answer": "Cross", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008ddb0f4f3bc4a292f8623", "question": "After World War II, who was the first leader of the Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia?", "answer": "Ivan Ribar (From December 29. 2945 until January 14, 1953, he was the President of the Federal Assembly of Yugoslavia.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a127cf93664eb10486bd", "question": "Jurgen Rumor, a former professional soccer player, hails from what European country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd93", "question": "Who merged with the struggling Cleveland Barons in 1978?", "answer": "The Minnesota North Stars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a76", "question": "On \"Sesame Street\", which two characters live in an apartment at 123 Sesame Street?", "answer": "Bert and Ernie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19b", "question": "Belle, Spike, Olaf, Marbles, and Andy are siblings of which Peanuts character?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e05cfe83fe1f2a824b8b", "question": "What German political leader was known as the \"Iron Chancellor\"?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f5", "question": "The Ozark Mountains are found predominantly in which two US states?", "answer": "Missouri and Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c220", "question": "When did \"Macho Man\" Randy Savage die?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff5", "question": "What is biltong?", "answer": "Dried meat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5902a033cad1ec93f27df768", "question": "What is typically added to Vietnamese iced coffee to sweeten it?", "answer": "Sweetened condensed milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaa", "question": "What is the state capital of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce7", "question": "What Nobel Prize-winning author committed suicide by gunshot in 1961?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898c", "question": "What snack gave Mickey Mouse his first spoken words?", "answer": "Hot dogs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd96a7423c87fd04dd15e12", "question": "As of 2020, which astronaut had spent the most time in space?", "answer": "Gennady Padalka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a896", "question": "What city is home to the Milad Tower?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc080ec223966ae8f885b", "question": "Which actor made his film debut in \"Back to the Future\" as one of Biff's cronies?", "answer": "Billy Zane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be57f955415ba52ed6f0aac", "question": "The Rijksmuseum is located in what European city?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ea", "question": "In which US state is Stone Mountain?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20e6631a458464a93c421", "question": "First published in 1842, \"The Masque of the Red Death\" is a short story by which American writer?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c11c", "question": "What year did the US first host the Summer Olympic Games?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff20f2f31a458464a93c42e", "question": "What is the name of the sailboat that is  featured in the book \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "The Satori", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d7", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Dnieper river?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51215ff04d658268c92cd", "question": "Who was the first American casualty in the American Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Crispus Attucks\u00a0was the first person killed in the Boston massacre and is widely considered to be the first American casualty.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e93567ccba3ffe45786c5", "question": "What word is used to describe \"bell shaped flowers\"?", "answer": "Campanulate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a8", "question": "What do the initials stand for in J. D. Salinger's name?", "answer": "Jerome David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d470e4f8e329de4f877896", "question": "What chemical compound causes pain in muscles after exercise?", "answer": "Lactic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b285", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb3", "question": "Which Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ab", "question": "What classification of rock covers approximately 75% of the Earth's surface?", "answer": "Sedimentary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049d99cf93664eb10486af", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e7", "question": "What was ALF's girlfriend from Melmac's name?", "answer": "Rhonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae26", "question": "Who did Anne Hathaway marry in 1582?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c9", "question": "What is the Heart of Gold in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "A space ship", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596dfd709616e6c6d4eba4f6", "question": "What country was the first to send an object to the Moon?", "answer": "The Soviet Union", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d6c12b42d4a3561a9f07", "question": "What sport is Tucker Dupree associated with?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aebf", "question": "In which country did fireworks originate?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594a64c22ebb971c1417fba7", "question": "Who was the first US actress to be featured on a US postage stamp?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7a49ff048f679a45abea", "question": "What part of the brain is responsible for vision?", "answer": "Occipital", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93f", "question": "What is the slowest moving, living land mammal?", "answer": "Three-toed sloth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff518b1ff04d658268c9300", "question": "For what is the Siberian Husky dog named Balto famous?", "answer": "When diphtheria hit Nome, Alaska in 1925, Balto led the mush team of Siberian Huskies carrying serum on the last leg of the trek.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96f0123c87fd04dd15e3f", "question": "The Black Death was caused by fleas carried by what animal?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51f", "question": "What does the abbreviation HTML stand for?", "answer": "HyperText Markup Language", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50f", "question": "What was the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e66", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Garfield?", "answer": "Lorenzo Music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa3d86ce05a3942286eab", "question": "Whose hand is shown drawing the charcoal portrait of Kate Winslet in \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "James Cameron's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a2", "question": "What was Michael Flaherty's job on the TV show \"Spin City\"?", "answer": "Deputy mayor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c889", "question": "What is the chemical name for a dentist's \"laughing gas\"?", "answer": "Nitrous oxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76673eec85e375820b280", "question": "Which two Great Lakes are connected by the Straits of Mackinac?", "answer": "Michigan and Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b65", "question": "How many of the seven dwarfs have beards?", "answer": "6", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a572", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for the state of Delaware?", "answer": "DE", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f28", "question": "\"The Great White Hope\" is a fictionalized account of what first black heavyweight champ?", "answer": "Jack Johnson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff0", "question": "What was Walt Disney's middle name?", "answer": "Elias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b8", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a267", "question": "What year did The Trammps release the song \"Disco Inferno\"?", "answer": "1976", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a037", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", Meg was an intern in the office of which elected official?", "answer": "Mayor West", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af0e", "question": "The Battle of Bunker Hill occurred during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c803", "question": "What trade name comes from combining the French words for velvet and hook?", "answer": "Velcro", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbc950a60f0007efaba0e5f", "question": "In Telltale's Season 1 of the \"The Walking Dead\" game series, what is the name of the main character?", "answer": "Lee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cbfe86de0eb824d4052d5", "question": "What strategically important island is part of the Hawaiian archipelago, but not the state of Hawaii?", "answer": "Midway Atoll -- It's instead a U.S. territory that is part of the U.S. Minor Outlying Islands.  It was annexed in 1867.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cdc83e347d002c297e4e8", "question": "In 1973 Roland Ohisson was buried in a coffin made of what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b313", "question": "The Suez Crisis of 1956 was precipitated by Egypt's plans to do what?", "answer": "Nationalize the Suez Canal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b183", "question": "What year was the Galapagos Islands archipelago declared a whale sanctuary?", "answer": "1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a06a", "question": "Who had a No. 1 R&B hit in US 1971 with \"Bridge over Troubled Water\"?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b699091e762b54eb9be9411", "question": "How is the number 20 written with Roman numerals?", "answer": "XX", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f369fa5fdd6dd25324da", "question": "Which film producer said \"Anyone who goes to a psychiatrist ought to have his head examined\"?", "answer": "Samuel Goldwyn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a620e2ebb971c1417fb8b", "question": "Which detective was played by Jack Webb in the 1960s TV show \"Dragnet\"?", "answer": "Sergeant Joe Friday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f457caf848b908361b873", "question": "Who became president of Brazil in 2019?", "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5afad941430e050a5df0d114", "question": "According to most sources, where is the world\u2019s tallest unclimbed unclimable mountain?", "answer": "Bhutan/China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e05cf4f3bc4a292f8631", "question": "What artist said, \"Every child is an artist\"?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso (The full quote reads,\u00a0\"Every child is an artist, the problem is staying an artist when you grow up.\")", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c423", "question": "What is the common name for the fruit known as \"Citrus grandis\"?", "answer": "Grapefruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c7", "question": "What planet was Mork from in the TV show \"Mork & Mindy\"?", "answer": "Ork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa5f20565ad31a57c817", "question": "Who was the mayor of Chicago from 1955 to 1976?", "answer": "Richard J. Daley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67e", "question": "How many points must the victor score in a game of cribbage?", "answer": "61 or 121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ea", "question": "Which is the highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77d3d824f0f7a362efd554", "question": "Who was the last man from the Apollo program to have walked on the Moon?", "answer": "Eugene Cernan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891f", "question": "What is the name of the dragon in \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Smaug", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b1", "question": "The port city of Sheboygan is located in which US state?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba497874c93a3298b2146", "question": "What is believed to have eventually killed Oliver Cromwell?", "answer": "Malaria and urinary/kidney infection", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac43", "question": "During World War I how did the Germany Army make ammonia for explosives?", "answer": "Using the Haber Process", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e942c7ccba3ffe45786cf", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Californium?", "answer": "Cf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59412664bab1e6f9796f1b58", "question": "How long does a day last on Uranus?", "answer": "17 hours", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18c", "question": "Who was the first woman to win an Oscar Best Actress in 1929?", "answer": "Janet Gaynor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c7ad877e98cb977789d5", "question": "What is the only country to lie entirely in the Alpine region?", "answer": "Lichtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe909eb01dd7bf43be5e893", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba2", "question": "What city is the setting for the TV series \"Mad Men\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a869", "question": "Andorra is landlocked by what two countries?", "answer": "France and Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc2f46bcee580c7f8fd1e58", "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2a", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Whyalla?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8b60ec223966ae8f883c", "question": "Lady Gaga derived her stage name from a song performed by which legendary band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339462", "question": "Who is Sulley's sidekick in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c2", "question": "What does the abbreviation N/A mean?", "answer": "Not applicable", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894e", "question": "What Paris cathedral's bells were rung by Quasimodo?", "answer": "Notre Dame's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b1743a7bb2d29f81593b6f5", "question": "Who wrote the Opera \"The Love for Three Oranges\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d1ca2596a59cbdfbd387", "question": "What was baseball great Jackie Robinson's uniform number?", "answer": "42", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8a6fec223966ae8f8831", "question": "In the movie \"Polar Express\", there is one rule when it comes to hot chocolate. What is it?", "answer": "Don't let it cool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbf59003d27d341092bd5", "question": "What is the only Central American country with English as an official language?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921fcdca4edfd43a087adc3", "question": "What number is represented by \"V\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909ce69bb53d1af658864f0", "question": "Who directed the 2003 film \"Elf\"?", "answer": "Jon Favreau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad45", "question": "Who was the first US president to take the oath of office using a nickname?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c5c63c99d48cd169b16", "question": "What is the name of Norman Rockwell\u2019s painting depicting a family holiday dinner?", "answer": "\"Freedom from Want\" -- It shows what many people picture to be the ideal Thanksgiving or Christmas dinner.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c59", "question": "Who played the role of the bodyguard in the 1992 movie \"The Bodyguard\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e932a7ccba3ffe45786c2", "question": "What painting technique uses colored pigments mixed with a binder, most common of which are egg yolks?", "answer": "Tempera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe655e3ae7e414034b5aebd", "question": "What Greek figure was famously forced to complete 12 Labors?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985a", "question": "In the movie \"Princess Mononoke\", the Forest Spirit most resembles what animal?", "answer": "A Stag", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfd6b9616e6c6d4eba4f5", "question": "What country was the first to send an object to the Moon?", "answer": "The Soviet Union", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9a", "question": "How many stars does the New Zealand national flag have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121a4763c99d48cd169b02", "question": "According to myth, who rode the flying horse named Sleipnir?", "answer": "Sleipnir, known as the fastest horses, carried Odin the All-Father through the sky, over the seas, and across the lands.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca9", "question": "What drink is made from fermented honey, yeast and water?", "answer": "Mead", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a307", "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Madeleine Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcae", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Mojito?", "answer": "Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339872", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", what does the bottle marked \"Drink Me\" do?", "answer": "Shrinks you", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17f", "question": "What was George Hepplewhite's profession?", "answer": "Furniture maker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fc", "question": "In the movie \"True Romance\", what was the name of Clarence Worley's love interest?", "answer": "Alabama Whitman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe904c801dd7bf43be5e877", "question": "The Miami Marlins' baseball stadium is built on the former site of what other stadium?", "answer": "The Orange Bowl Stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e8f106d333868d34d74f", "question": "Which country's traditional name translates to \"Land of the Thunder Dragon\"?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a51", "question": "What was the complete name of the toga party band from the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "Otis Day & the Knights", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e34", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The Boy Who Lived\"?", "answer": "Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9f", "question": "During what war was the construction of the Pentagon completed?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac36", "question": "By the end of the 20th Century, what war saw the most Americans die?", "answer": "The US Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee1", "question": "Whom did James Earl Ray assassinate?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9444574a5ce6b56b8247", "question": "What was Agatha Christie's second husband's profession?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39e", "question": "Which is bigger, the state of Florida or England?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078c700eee65b76b9f2673", "question": "What is the Statue of Liberty holding in her left hand?", "answer": "She holds a tablet inscribed with the date of the U.S. Declaration of Independence \u2014 July 4, 1776. It is nearly 24 ft. long.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd82415d0de9af39e9d46b7", "question": "How deep in the ocean is the wreckage of the Titanic?", "answer": "2.4 miles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aad", "question": "For whom did Robert May write the story of Rudolph the Red-nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "His daughter, Barbara", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fd", "question": "What year did Frederick Forsyth publish the novel \"The Fist of God\"?", "answer": "1994", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f5", "question": "In what U.S. City was the Rag\u00fa brand of Italian-style sauces first produced?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65e861f3c0ead6880d62e", "question": "Where did Britain restore parliamentary powers after Sinn Fein agreed to disarm?", "answer": "Northern Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b578", "question": "How many teaspoons are there in a cup?", "answer": "48", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888b", "question": "Where was King Arthur's court?", "answer": "Camelot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f62", "question": "What two Top Ten Creedence Clearwater Revival hits ask about the rain?", "answer": "\"Have You Ever Seen the Rain\" and \"Who'll Stop the Rain\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76e69eec85e375820b2dd", "question": "Which country is famously shaped like an elephant's head?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febaf0d7e83c707845b20fa", "question": "What is the most venomous fish in the world?", "answer": "Reef stonefish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa6296ce05a3942286ecc", "question": "In the film \"Fargo\", Frances McDormand plays the pregnant police chief of what town?", "answer": "Bernard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe734e4eec85e375820b23e", "question": "Which of Adolf Hitler's close associates fled to Scotland?", "answer": "Rudolph Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd4", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"P\"?", "answer": "Papa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c56e877e98cb977789ae", "question": "Where is Africa's westernmost point?", "answer": "Cape Verde", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba06", "question": "What sport did George Bush Sr. play at Yale University?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab86", "question": "Where is the lowest elevation in the US?", "answer": "Death Valley", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a682", "question": "Which states share a border with South Carolina?", "answer": "Georgia and North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5954e9c48e82ccaf3b9a67bd", "question": "What food group is a cucumber technically in?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a6c020565ad31a57c7de", "question": "What city is the home of the Liberty Bell?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"luau\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1dc", "question": "Who played the leading female part in the 1954 film \"A Star Is Born\"?", "answer": "Judy Garland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6bc", "question": "What separates the twin cities of Minneapolis and Saint Paul?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067efeff9c0647b50a8080", "question": "What actor played the role of Dr. Frederick Frankenstein in the 1974 film \"Young Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe000991cf6db9ac4808d14", "question": "In what city was \"The Star-Spangled Banner\" written?", "answer": "Baltimore, Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121bc863c99d48cd169b10", "question": "When someone is breviloquent, they use very few what?", "answer": "Words -- Eloquent people speak beautifully and often at length, whereas breviloquent people like to keep it brief.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6af", "question": "What do climbers rub on their hands for extra grip?", "answer": "Chalk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f2", "question": "What US state has been governed by Evan Mecham and Bruce Babbitt?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf9", "question": "Captain Nemo is a character in which book?", "answer": "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3ad4ff048f679a45ab2f", "question": "What is the shape of DNA known as?", "answer": "Double Helix", "category": "science"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe656eeae7e414034b5aed4", "question": "The ancient city of Chich\u00e9n Itz\u00e1 was built by which civilization?", "answer": "The Mayans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a4a2cf93664eb10486c5", "question": "Early on in the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what type of car does Freddie brag about driving?", "answer": "A Porsche", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6e", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Fred Jones?", "answer": "The Mystery Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c699877e98cb977789bc", "question": "Where can you drive the \"Extraterrestrial Highway\"?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa6", "question": "In 1987, what song was the first in Spanish to top the US charts?", "answer": "La Bamba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a44c", "question": "In what country was the Terracotta Army sealed underground?", "answer": "China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "593c4ba4b8198b9a2b077965", "question": "Who is Scarlett's first husband who died in the Civil War in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Charles Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e86c964118b2bb3809c5", "question": "In Slovenia, Saint Valentine is considered the saint of good health and the patron of whom?", "answer": "Beekeepers and pilgrims", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8893ec223966ae8f8820", "question": "Which singer began her rise to superstardom actually as a dancer on a sketch-comedy television program?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez (she was a dancer on the Wayans Brothers' TV Show \"In Living Color\")", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa57", "question": "Which country has Budapest as its capital?", "answer": "Hungary", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30d", "question": "Who uttered the line \"Who am I? Why am I here?\" during a debate?", "answer": "James Stockdale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3e", "question": "Who is Holden Caulfield's sister in \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "Phoebe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c8defbde8045e48466e2", "question": "What do plants produce through photosynthesis?", "answer": "Plants use energy from the sun to turn carbon dioxide into food. Carbohydrates and oxygen are the end result of photosynthesis.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12a", "question": "Who did Idi Amin succeed as president of Uganda?", "answer": "Milton Obote", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e3", "question": "What letter appears on the left end of the bottom letter row of a traditional QWERTY keyboard?", "answer": "The letter Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5d285dad637d903c8822", "question": "What is Valentine's Day called in Brazil?", "answer": "Dia dos Namorados", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01a", "question": "Ranger VII was the first US spacecraft to send back pictures of what?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe767e2eec85e375820b299", "question": "What is the most populous city in Canada", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b771", "question": "How long is a lane in a bowling alley, measured from the foul line to the head pin?", "answer": "60 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339845", "question": "Julie Andrews won an Oscar for her role in what Disney classic?", "answer": "Mary Poppins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d968908b8581f80b092a7", "question": "How old did Canada turn on July 1, 2017?", "answer": "150 years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba16a874c93a3298b2126", "question": "What is Kenny G's real surname?", "answer": "Gorelick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73f", "question": "What toy company first produced the Spirograph drawing toy back in 1966?", "answer": "Kenner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a6", "question": "Zoologist Dian Fossey dedicated her life to the study of what animals?", "answer": "Gorillas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa6", "question": "What is a group of locusts called?", "answer": "Plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded270ea2747c8aff16d3d", "question": "Whose military autobiography was titled \"Crusade in Europe\"?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7c", "question": "What nickname was given to Al Capone?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f79", "question": "What was Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339626", "question": "What movie starring George Clooney and Mark Wahlberg takes place during the Gulf War?", "answer": "Three Kings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29c", "question": "What is the astronomical term for the distance light travels in a vacuum in one year?", "answer": "Light-year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4edc106d333868d34d770", "question": "What do you call the moveable indicator on a Ouija board which is shaped like a heart?", "answer": "Planchette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8aa8101dd7bf43be5e75c", "question": "What type of dog is \"Handsome Dan\", the mascot of Yale University?", "answer": "Bulldog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29a", "question": "What US politician was named for Julius Caesar?", "answer": "J. C. Watts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea824fff048f679a45ac20", "question": "What color is second from the top in a rainbow?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b34", "question": "What woodwind instrument is sometimes called a \"licorice stick\"?", "answer": "Clarinet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a5", "question": "What year was the inaugural FIFA World Cup tournament held?", "answer": "1930", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a4", "question": "What director died four months before the release of his movie \"Eyes Wide Shut\"?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfdd", "question": "What was the first product to have a barcode?", "answer": "Wrigley's gum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133976c", "question": "What Will Ferrell movie is about three gun men who start a fraternity and re-live their college years?", "answer": "Old School", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338911", "question": "What was the name of the cat in Walt Disney's movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bfe006ab668d7dfe168b5c2", "question": "What metal impurity makes rubies red and emeralds green?", "answer": "Chromium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399d6", "question": "What were the names of Roseanne\u2019s two daughters on the TV show \"Roseanne\"?", "answer": "Becky and Darlene", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc6", "question": "Who rode Rocinante?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66dc0a5bfecdd737e08a6", "question": "How many candles are lit throughout the eight nights of Hanukkah?", "answer": "44", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab4", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Ecuador?", "answer": "Andean condor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c412", "question": "What bird has the biggest eyes of any land animal?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eb0f6f83302ff91e464a2", "question": "What company makes the Vince Lombardi Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8836ce05a3942286d6f", "question": "A silhouette of which player is widely recognized as the inspiration behind the official NBA logo designed in 1969?", "answer": "Jerry West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d78", "question": "What movie features three tunnels named Tom, Dick, and Harry?", "answer": "The Great Escape", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be9", "question": "Which instrument does the Leader of an orchestra play?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23a", "question": "What Australian rock band release the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937eed008d98002fdd633d8", "question": "From which musical did \"One Night in Bangkok Makes a Hard Man Humble\" and \"I Know Him So Well\" come?", "answer": "Chess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e8", "question": "What cartoon legend became the first licensed lunch box character back in 1935?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3b5eff048f679a45ab34", "question": "A group of tigers is called what?", "answer": "An ambush", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5b", "question": "What Broadway great's daughter wrote the book \"Freaky Friday\"?", "answer": "Richard Rodgers'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd72", "question": "What is sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590722e33745b36be7303a03", "question": "What popular Christmas song did Eartha Kitt record in 1953?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b922", "question": "What age milestone qualifies you to be a \"super centenarian\"?", "answer": "110", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b591", "question": "What does the abbreviation MBA stand for in the MBA master's degree designation?", "answer": "Master of Business Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3e", "question": "What does pink kryptonite do to Superman?", "answer": "It turns him temporarily gay", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2a", "question": "What boxer was nicknamed the \"Manassa Mauler\"?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7b", "question": "What team did the Atlanta Braves defeat in the 1995 World Series?", "answer": "Cleveland Indians", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25938658e585fda9cfa41", "question": "What shape is \"chiocciole\" pasta?", "answer": "Snail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f72bba9e54d890926f6ed", "question": "Six Flags, the famous Texas amusement park, was named after what?", "answer": "The six governments that have ruled Texas -- Specifically, France, Spain, Mexico, the Confederacy, Texas and the U.S.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b893", "question": "Who was the last tennis player to win a Grand Slam using a wooden racquet?", "answer": "Bjorn Borg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913f", "question": "Who composed the opera \"Death in Venice\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Britten", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c759", "question": "What human organs are affected by glaucoma?", "answer": "The eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a612", "question": "Which is the third largest Caribbean island?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd65bbaa5bfecdd737e082e", "question": "What was the last album recorded by the Beatles?", "answer": "Abbey Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84d", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the cochlea?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad9dc69e748bb36357acddd", "question": "What 21st-century US presidential candidate had a spouse who was president of two colleges?", "answer": "Bernie Sanders", "category": "history"}]